♪ ♪
HICCUP:
This is Berk.
So far off the map that
it might as well not exist.
My village?
In a word, sturdy.
It’s been here for generations,
but every single building
is new.
The air is crisp,
the water is clean,
and the views are nothing
to complain about.
The only downsides
are the pests.
[bell clanging]
You see, most places
have mice or mosquitoes.
We have...
[flame whooshing]
[grunts, whimpers]
[panting]
Dragons.
[groans]
[frantic chatter]
HICCUP:
Most people would leave.
Not us.
We’re Vikings.
We don’t run from fights.
We start them.
- Hey! Hiccup!
- Evening.
Go home!
I will just as soon as I, uh...
You’re in the way again!
♪ ♪
VIKING:
Hiccup, play dead!
HICCUP:
You see, dragons have been
a bit of a problem.
Here and, well, everywhere.
So we decided to take
the fight to them.
-  -How’s that working out for us?
- [sheep bleats, squeals]
Eh...
- [explosive whooshing]
- [gasps]
- Whoa!
- What are you doing?
- What is he doing out again?
- [chuckling]
- Get inside. Go on.
- [grunts]
HICCUP:
That’s Stoick the Vast,
chief of the tribe.
[screaming]
They say, when he was a baby,
he popped a dragon’s head
clean off its shoulders.
- Do I believe it?
- [yells]
- Yes, I do.
- What have we got?
Gronckles, Nadders,
Zipplebacks, Skrills.
Snorti spotted
a Monstrous Nightmare.
Any Night Furies?
None so far, Chief.
Good.
- Follow me.
- HÜRL: Right, Chief.
STOICK:
Come on, you wretches!
HÜRL:
You heard him. Come on, lads.
♪ ♪
Oh. Out again?
HICCUP:
Just pretend I’m not even here.
I’ll be in and out
before you can say...
Not so fast.
[groans] Come on, please.
The meathead with attitude
and interchangeable hands
is Gobber.
Here. Go on.
HICCUP:
I’ve been his apprentice
- ever since I was little.
- I’m keeping my eye on you.
I’m not even supposed
to be out here.
Ha! Since when did that
ever stop you?
[clamoring]
STOICK:
Guard the food stores.
- Aye, Chief.
- Protect the livestock.
HÜRL:
Aye, Stoick.
And keep an ear out
for Night Furies.
[screaming]
GOBBER:
Hammer.
- [flame whooshing]
- [Vikings screaming]
TUFFNUT:
Fire brigade!
HICCUP:
Ah, the fire brigade.
Berk’s cool kids.
They get to be out
in the action.
ASTRID:
Guys, out of the way!
HICCUP:
But they’re nothing
without their captain,
the shining star
of our generation.
A-Amazing without even trying.
The one that smokes them all.
[sighs] Astrid.
♪ ♪
What?
Uh...
Shouldn’t you be in bed?
[laughs]
[sighs]
GOBBER:
Come on, back to work.
You know,
I need to get out there.
Show my stuff, make my mark.
You’ve made plenty of marks,
all in the wrong places.
Give me two minutes.
I’ll-I’ll take down a dragon.
My life will get
infinitely better.
I might even get a girlfriend.
VIKING: There’s a Zippleback
behind you!
Astrid? [laughs]
But she’s a real Viking.
You can’t wield a hammer.
You can’t swing an axe.
You can’t even throw
one of these.
See, but this...
this will throw it for me.
- Oh, another one.
- It’s fully redesigned.
It-it’s...
- Whoa!
- Whew!
- HICCUP: It’s, uh...
- [groans]
double-barreled.
You see, this right here...
this is what I’m talking about.
Okay, this is a mild cal...
mild calibration issue.
If you ever want
to get out there
and start fighting dragons,
you’ve got to stop all of...
all of this.
You just gestured to all of me.
Yeah. Stop being all of you.
Oh...
Oh, yeah.
You, sir, are playing
a dangerous game.
- [gasping]
- Keeping this contained?
- There will be consequences.
- [grunts]
Well, I will take my chances.
Sword-- sharpen. Now.
HICCUP:
One day, I’ll get out there.
Because killing a dragon
is everything around here.
Gronckles are tough.
Taking one down
would at least get me noticed.
- A Zippleback?
- [frantic shouting]
Exotic, exciting.
Two heads, twice the status.
Lopping off a Nadder’s head
would definitely show them
I belong.
[snarling]
- [sheep bleating]
- [dragon snarling]
VIKING:
Come on, lads!
RETCHA:
They found the sheep.
Then let loose
with everything we’ve got.
HICCUP:
And then there’s
the Monstrous Nightmare.
[roars]
Reload!
HICCUP: Only the best Vikings
go after those.
- [grunting]
- [dragon snarling, screeching]
But the ultimate prize
is the dragon
that no one has ever seen.
- We call it the...
- Night Fury!
- Jump!
- [whooshing]
GOBBER:
And we’ve got a Night Fury.
Never steals food,
never shows itself.
And never misses.
[grunts]
Time for old Gobber
to take over.
- [flame whooshing]
- [indistinct shouting]
Stay put here.
Here. I’m serious.
HICCUP: No one has
ever killed a Night Fury.
GOBBER:
Attack!
HICCUP: That’s why
I’m going to be the first.
- You again? Get back inside!
- I’ll make a point of it.
LOOGI: You’re going to get
yourself killed, Hiccup!
HICCUP:
I know! Sorry.
[sheep bleating]
Here, give me that. [grunts]
[squeals]
[grunting]
Mind yourself!
This Nadder still has
some fire in it.
♪ ♪
[whispering]:
Come on.
Give me something to shoot at.
Come on, show yourself.
[whooshing]
[grunts]
- [dragon screeching]
- I hit it.
[shouts excitedly]
- I hit it!
- [growling]
Did anybody see that?
Except for you.
[Hiccup screaming]
HICCUP:
Oh, gods. [screams]
Spitelout,
do not let that escape.
[sighs] Thanks a lot.
[grunting]
[whimpers]
[dragon snarling]
[screeches]
STOICK:
You’re all out.
Let’s see what else
you’re made of.
[grunting fiercely]
Aye, that’s what I thought.
HICCUP: Oh, and there’s one
more thing to know.
[creaking]
VIKING:
Look out!
[whimpers]
[sighs]
Sorry, Dad.
- SPITELOUT: Watch out!
- [yelling]
[sheep squeals]
[sheep bleating]
♪ ♪
[sighs]
Okay, but I hit a Night Fury.
[Stoick grunts]
Dad, this isn’t like
any other time.
I mean, I really hit one.
Aye, a dragon
no one’s ever seen.
Because it uses night
as its camouflage.
If you squint, you can see it
blotting out the stars.
- That’s how I shot it down.
- Stop!
Stop.
Every time you step outside,
disaster happens.
Can you not see
that I have bigger problems?
Winter is almost here,
and I have an entire village
to feed.
Between you and me,
the village could do
with a little less feeding.
This isn’t a joke, Hiccup!
Why can’t you follow
the simplest orders?
Because I can’t stop myself.
Okay? I see a dragon,
and I have to just... kill it.
You know, i-it’s...
it’s who I am.
[sighs]
You are many things, son,
but a dragon killer
is not one of them.
Get back to the house.
Make sure he stays there.
How much can
one person mess up?
Anyone else would have been
booted off the island by now.
I guess being son of the chief
has its privileges.
If not for the chief, though...
[grunts] Anyway, my dad’s
super proud of me, so...
[sighs]
[laughing]:
Dad, I was just talking...
Don’t talk to me in public.
[chuckles]
HICCUP:
You know, I really did hit one.
GOBBER:
Of course you did, Hiccup.
He never listens.
Well, that runs in the family.
And-and when he does,
it’s always with
some disappointed scowl,
like somebody forgot
the meat in the stew.
[chuckles] I’ve seen that look.
Oi. You’re thinking
about this all wrong, eh?
It’s not so much
what you look like.
It’s what’s inside of you
he can’t stand.
Thank you for summing that up.
W-Wait. The point is...
stop trying so hard
to be something you’re not.
I just want to be
one of you guys.
[door closes]
I know you do.
♪ ♪
[clamoring]
No one said it would be easy!
[clamoring stops]
But may I remind you,
we are all descendants
of the finest dragon fighters
from everywhere
Vikings have traveled,
who gathered here
because they knew
that we were within
spitting distance
of a key dragon’s nest.
If we can just take it,
we can wipe out the devils
for good.
Take it? We can’t even find it.
- [murmuring]
- RETCHA: Exactly.
This nest is starting to sound
more and more
like a fairy tale.
We’re exhausted.
And what do we have
to show for it, eh?
VIKINGS:
Nothing!
We have purpose.
- [laughter]
- Oh, come on.
We are the warriors of Berk,
the roughest, toughest tribe
this side of the sun.
No? [scoffs]
Phlegma.
We watched you take down
a Zippleback singlehandedly.
I mean, sure, you lost your leg
in the process,
but you came out on top,
didn’t you?
- Well... [stammers]
- STOICK: Yes, you did.
Retcha, your people came
from the Far East.
Fungi, yours all the way
from-from the Silk Road.
Loogi, your people came
from the sunbaked coasts
of Bláland.
And look at us.
We’re still here.
We’re still fighting.
We’re still watching
each other’s backs.
So are we really gonna pack up
and go home
while these bloody beasts
are still a threat
to all of our lands?
Is that who we are?
- VIKINGS: No.
- Is it?
- No.
- Is it?!
No!
Is it?!
Is it?
Uh, no, Chief, I guess not.
That’s what I thought.
Elder Gothi, give us a sign.
Do we stand a chance
of finding the nest
before the ice sets in?
Then that’s all I need.
Back into the fog we go.
All right, everyone.
- Prepare the ships!
- [cheering]
Let’s go!
♪ ♪
Do I take my bucket hand
for when they burn our ships
or my swimming hand
for when they sink them?
STOICK:
Not so fast, Gobber.
I don’t have time to train
this year’s recruits,
so you’ll do it.
Ah, the old rite of passage.
Hiccup’s just come of age,
hasn’t he?
[scoffs] I meant the others.
Yeah, so while I’m busy,
he’ll c-cover the stall.
Molten steel,
razor-sharp blades,
lots of time on his hands.
What could possibly go wrong?
Oh, what am I gonna do
with him, Gobber?
[sighs] Stick him in training.
No. I’m serious.
Yeah, so am I.
The kid wants this
more than anything.
- [Stoick scoffs]
- Believe it or not,
that young man actually
wants to make you proud.
But he’s got a mind of his own.
Gets that from his mother.
[scoffs]
Look what happened to her.
Yeah, ’cause Valka was
the stubborn one.
- See, when I was a boy...
- Oh, here we go.
I-I followed orders.
Right? I worked hard.
Because I believed
in what a-a Viking could do.
Crush mountains,
level forests, tame seas.
I knew what I was
and what I had to become.
Hiccup is... he’s not that boy.
What chance does he have
of following in my footsteps?
GOBBER:
Yeah.
[Stoick sighs]
You can’t stop him, Stoick.
You can only prepare him.
Because the truth is
we aren’t always gonna
be around to protect him.
He’s gonna get out there again.
[chuckles]
He’s probably out there now.
♪ ♪
[birds chirping]
[sighs]
[grunts]
[yells]
How could I lose
an entire dragon?!
[grunts]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
[panting sharply]
[chuckles softly]
I did it.
I did it!
- [dragon groaning]
- [gasps]
[panting]
Oh, why couldn’t you
have been dead?
Now I have to kill you.
♪ ♪
[dragon groans softly]
[Hiccup panting sharply]
[whimpers]
[groaning]
[groans]
[sighs]
[dragon groaning]
[dragon moans in pain]
[takes deep breath]
[blade slicing through ropes]
[roars]
[growling]
[gasping breaths]
[high-pitched roaring]
[exhales sharply]
[roaring]
[dragon squealing in distance]
[sighs]
Hiccup.
Dad. Uh...
Look, I need
to talk to you, Dad.
I need to speak
with you, too, son.
I’ve decided I don’t want
- to fight dragons.
- I think it’s time
you learn to fight dragons.
BOTH:
What?
Well, you go first.
No, no, no, no.
You-you go first.
You get your wish.
Dragon training.
Start in the morning.
Oh, man, I really
should’ve gone first.
You know,
’cause I-I was thinking,
we have a surplus
of dragon-fighting Vikings,
but do we have enough
bread-making Vikings or...
You’ll need this.
Dad... I don’t want
to fight dragons.
[laughing]:
Come on.
Yes, you do.
No, let me rephrase.
I can’t kill dragons.
But you will.
No, I’m very extra sure
that I won’t.
It’s time, Hiccup.
Uh... can you not hear me?
Can you not hear me?!
The Trial of Flame is
where Vikings are made.
Where heroes are forged,
where future chiefs are born.
I... I’m none of those things.
I’m not like you, Dad.
♪ ♪
[sighs]
Listen.
When you carry this axe,
you carry all of us with you.
Which means you walk like us,
you talk like us,
you think like us.
No more of... this.
You just gestured to all of me.
Deal?
This conversation is feeling
very one-sided.
Deal?
Deal.
Good.
[sighs]
Train hard.
I’ll be back.
Probably.
[door closes]
And I’ll be here.
Maybe.
♪ ♪
GOBBER:
Welcome to the Trial of Flame.
SNOTLOUT: The moment
we’ve all been waiting for.
I just got to pick a spot
for my statue.
It’s so much bigger
from down here.
Can you guys believe
we’re actually standing here?
This is where Chief Greybile
slew the Whispering Death.
Yeah, and it’s where
Chief Tuffnut
will slay everything else.
- Watch and learn.
- Man, I can’t wait
to get some
legendary war wounds!
Yeah, like a nasty gash
right across my face.
- Call me boring...
- Boring.
...but I’m just excited to see
some real live dragons
up close.
You know, I could do without
the permanent injuries and...
Oh, where’s the glory in that?
Yeah, it’s only fun
if you get a scar out of it.
HICCUP [chuckling]:
I know, right?
Pain.
Love it.
Oh, great. Who let him in?
Mm, I guess Daddy pulled
some strings, huh?
Aren’t you two, like,
a little old to be here?
- Ouch.
- Wait, what did you say, whippersnapper?
What did you say?
Can you say it again?
Yeah, touchy subject.
They’ve flunked dragon training
a few times.
Um, it was four times,
actually.
Yeah, and it’s called
being held back.
As in too valuable
to let go of.
Real sensitive, Hiccup.
Nice name, by the way.
Your name is Snotlout.
Exactly.
It’s a manly Viking name.
Translates from
the ancient texts as
"one who beateth the snot
out of a..."
GOBBER:
Shut up.
Let’s get started.
Bloody kids.
You are now the latest to join
this time-honored tradition.
Every toe biter
born into our tribe
must one day survive this arena
if they ever hope to do battle
alongside the rest of us.
It will be grueling.
And it will be
very, very dangerous.
But whoever does best will win
the title of Top Slayer.
And with it...
And with it, the honor
of killing their first dragon
in front of the entire village.
There is no greater glory.
What?
Hiccup already killed
a Night Fury,
so does that, like, what,
disqualify him or...
GOBBER:
Oh, ignore him.
You’re skinny.
You’re weak.
That’ll make you
less of a target.
They’ll see you
as slim pickings.
Not worth the effort.
They’ll go
after the more, uh...
Viking-like teens instead.
[dragons snarling, hissing]
Behind these doors are just
a few of the many species
you will learn to fight.
- The Deadly Nadder.
- [dragon snarls]
Attack eight, armor 16.
GOBBER:
The Hideous Zippleback.
Plus 11 stealth, times two.
The Monstrous Nightmare.
- Firepower 15.
- GOBBER: The Terrible Terror.
- Attack eight, venom 12!
- Will you stop that!
You big bag of wool.
And finally,
the gruesome Gronckle.
[quietly]:
Jaw strength eight.
- [dragon snarling]
- [thumping, chain rattling]
Uh, hey, big guy,
aren’t you gonna, like,
teach us something first?
I believe in learning
on the job.
[snarling]
Today is all about defense.
If you get blasted, you’re out.
Or, you know, dead.
So what’s the first thing
you’re gonna need?
- A shield!
- GOBBER: Shield, yes. Go.
- TUFFNUT: Out of my way.
- RUFFNUT: That one’s mine!
Shield is your most important
piece of equipment.
If you have to choose between
a weapon and a shield...
Just put it down.
Take the shield.
- RUFFNUT: Give it!
- TUFFNUT: Mine, mine, mine!
Find your own shield!
[grunting]
[both yelp]
GOBBER:
Ruffnut, Tuffnut, you’re out.
Shields are good
for another thing: noise.
Make plenty of it
to throw off the dragon’s aim.
[clanging]
Remember, all dragons have
a limited number of blasts.
How many does a Gronckle have?
Ooh, ooh! Six!
Six, yes.
That’s one for each of you.
FISHLEGS:
Although, interesting tidbit,
rocks from different regions
vary in mineral comp...
What are you do...
What are you doing?
Get in there!
Fishlegs, you’re out.
- ASTRID: Four shots left.
- SNOTLOUT: Yeah.
We’re pretty much gonna be
the stars of this thing.
Almost like we were meant
to be together.
It’s an elimination game,
genius.
There’s only one Top Slayer.
- [whooshing]
- [yelps]
GOBBER:
Snotlout, you’re done. [laughs]
Three shots.
Looks like it’s just
you and me, huh?
Nope. Just me.
Hey! Eyes on me!
[yells]
GOBBER:
Yes. Well done, Astrid.
Two shots left.
Oh, come on.
- Hiccup, you’re out.
- [whimpering]
- One shot left.
- RUFFNUT: Hey, watch it!
[gasping, whimpering]
GOBBER:
Hiccup!
[grunts] End of lesson.
[straining]
Back to bed,
you overgrown sausage.
[dragon grumbling]
Remember, a dragon
will always, always...
...go for the kill.
[sizzling]
♪ ♪
[sighs]
So, why didn’t you?
[birds squawking]
♪ ♪
[birds chirping]
- [dragon roaring]
- [gasping]
[pained shrieking]
Okay.
[squeals, groans]
[dragon moaning softly]
[dragon groaning]
♪ ♪
[groans]
[grunts]
Huh.
- [Hiccup gasps]
- [rattling]
[growls softly]
[thunder rumbling]
GOBBER:
Let’s review, shall we?
Where did Astrid go wrong
in the ring today?
ASTRID:
I mistimed my somersault dive.
It was sloppy.
It threw off my reverse tumble.
- Uh, yeah. We noticed.
- Hey.
Back off my girl. All right?
- She’s trying her best.
- SNOTLOUT: Yeah.
Don’t beat yourself up.
You’ll get it.
Just follow my lead next time.
[pained yell]
GOBBER:
Astrid’s right.
You’ve got to be tough
on yourselves.
All it takes is one weak link.
You made it, then?
You got to start
taking this seriously,
because we are living
in a battleground.
And in case
you haven’t noticed, the other side is winning.
You’re gonna need
every advantage you can get.
So, if you haven’t done
your homework,
allow me to present to you...
♪ ♪
...the Book of Dragons.
Everything we know
about every dragon we know of.
Each of your tribes
brought their wisdom
and experience to these pages.
It’s our most hallowed
possession.
[thunder crashes]
No dragon raids tonight,
so study up.
[Tuffnut stammering]
You mean read?
I’ve read it
like a hundred times.
There’s a Scauldron that sprays
your face with boiling water.
And then there’s,
um, another...
Why would I read words
when I can just kill the stuff
the words tell me stuff about?
Right? I mean, like,
I’m the kind of guy
that other guys
write word books about.
SNOTLOUT [chuckling]:
Nice.
- SNOTLOUT and TUFFNUT: Boys!
- FISHLEGS: Don’t worry, though.
I’m here for all of your
dragon-related inquiries, okay?
Theories, stats.
I’ve even made,
um, cards, um...
You can ask me anything.
- RUFFNUT: Stop following me.
- FISHLEGS: Here.
How about now? Try me now.
RUFFNUT:
Absolutely not.
So...
sounds like a gruesome,
grisly, good time, huh?
Read it.
Y-You know, uh...
maybe they’re not as bad
as we think they are.
Are you actually insane,
or do you just act that way?
Is-is there...
is there a third option?
Wiping out dragons
is why we’re here.
It’s why the best
of our tribes came together.
Because yes, dragons are
as bad as we think.
Y-Yeah, I-I know.
I’m just saying,
maybe we’re part
of the problem.
You know, moving in on
their lands, eating their food.
Wow.
You live in
a different world, don’t you?
What?
Just coast by,
taking it all for granted.
Well, I don’t think that...
Never having to work
for anything,
never struggling
to get a foot up.
Well, guess what.
I come from nothing.
No chief for a dad,
no handouts, no excuses.
I’m not afraid of hard work.
I’m willing to do whatever
it takes to get the job done,
which, in this case,
means wiping out the dragons
for the good of everyone.
Yeah.
You know what else?
I’m-I’m afraid...
afraid to ask.
I’ve got my eye
on that big house of yours.
I’m gonna be chief one day.
I-I don’t doubt it.
Actually, I think
my dad would be thrilled.
Besides, you’re the kid
he always hoped for.
Instead, he got...
all this.
Stay out of my way, Hiccup.
♪ ♪
[sighs]
[thunder crashes]
"Dragon classifications.
"Strike class. Fear class.
Mystery class.
"Thunderdrum.
"When startled, the Thunderdrum
produces a concussive sound
"that can kill a man
at close range.
"Extremely dangerous.
Kill on sight.
"Timberjack.
"Skrill. Whispering Death.
"Burns its victims.
Buries its victims.
"Chokes its victims.
Turns its victims inside out.
"Extremely dangerous.
Extremely dangerous.
"Kill on sight. Kill on sight.
Kill on sight.
"Night Fury.
"Size: unknown. Speed: unknown.
"The unholy offspring
of lightning and death itself.
Never engage this dragon."
STOICK:
I can almost smell them.
Take us in to Helheim’s Gate.
Here we go again.
Hard to port!
SPITELOUT:
- Set the oars! Furl the sails!
- [others chattering]
All together.
Come on.
Higher.
[chatter continues
indistinctly]
♪ ♪
[rocks clattering]
[ship scraping along rocks]
We’re not alone!
- Look up!
- Watch your heads!
[dragon snarling]
[frantic chatter]
[screaming]
[frantic chatter continues]
Turn back!
- PHLEGMA: They’re everywhere!
- [screeching]
Hey, I just, uh...
I just happened to notice
that the book had nothing
on Night Furies.
Is there maybe, like,
like, another book?
Maybe, like,
a Night Fury pamph...
[screeching, snarling]
GOBBER:
Focus, Hiccup.
You’re not even trying.
Today is about attack.
Nadders are quick
and light on their feet.
Your job is to be quicker
and lighter.
[panting]
- [gasps]
- [snarls, shrieks]
- [grunts]
- Sorry. [whimpers]
I’m really beginning to
question your teaching methods!
GOBBER:
Look for its blind spot.
Every dragon has one.
Find it, hide in it,
then strike.
[groans] Do you ever bathe?
If you don’t like it, go find
your own blind spot. Go!
- [whimpering]
- GOBBER: Blind spot, yes.
Deaf spot, not so much.
[laughs]
TUFFNUT:
I am hurt. I am very much hurt.
So, how does one sneak up
on a Night Fury?
No one has ever met one
and lived to tell the tale.
- Now, get in there!
- Yeah, I-I know.
I-I’m just saying, like,
- how would...
- ASTRID: Hiccup.
Down.
[panting quietly]
[dragon growling softly]
[snarling]
- SNOTLOUT: Whoa, save yourself!
- [Astrid grunts]
I’ll take care of this.
[grunting]
Oh.
Not my fault, Astrid.
I got distracted
by the light in your eyes.
[dragon snarling]
[dragon shrieking, roaring]
[pained shrieking]
- [grunting]
- HICCUP: Wait! Just let me...
[grunts fiercely]
[dragon shrieking]
- [Astrid grunting]
- [dragon whimpers]
Yes. Well done, Astrid.
Nothing like giving them
a taste of
their own medicine, eh?
Also, "Well done, Snotlout,
with the assist," right?
What a team!
Is anyone taking this
seriously?!
Take it seriously.
’Cause in case you forgot,
our parents’ war
is about to become ours!
Figure out
which side you’re on.
♪ ♪
[grunting, panting]
[distant birdcalls]
♪ ♪
[sighs]
[gasping breaths]
[growling softly]
Hmm? Huh?
[sniffing]
[growls softly]
[dragon snarls]
[knife splashes in water]
[exhales sharply]
[sniffing softly]
Huh. Toothless.
I could’ve sworn you had...
...teeth.
[growling softly]
[stammering]:
I don’t have any more.
[Hiccup panting]
[Toothless moans softly]
[Toothless retching]
[groans]
[Toothless moans gently]
Thanks?
[moans, grunts]
[whimpers]
Oh, come on.
You’re kidding, right?
[purrs]
[sighs]
[takes deep breath]
[grunts]
Mmm.
- Hmm?
- [Toothless moans softly]
[whimpers]
[groans]
- [Toothless grunts]
- [sighs]
[gagging]
[grunts]
[sighs]
[chuckles, sighs]
[chittering]
[growling]
[moans softly]
[moans]
- [growls]
- [Hiccup gasps]
[moans]
♪ ♪
[moans softly]
[Toothless breathing heavily]
[Toothless moaning curiously]
[branch snaps]
[dragging]
[Toothless moaning]
[moans]
♪ ♪
[growls]
[moans]
[growls, moans]
[growls]
[moans]
♪ ♪
[Toothless grunting]
[moans, growls]
♪ ♪
[moans softly]
[exhales sharply]
GOBBER: And then
he turned and grabbed me arm,
and with one twist,
he took my hand clean off
and he swallowed it whole.
Yeah, he must have spread
the word around,
’cause within a month,
another one had taken my leg.
FISHLEGS:
Probably a Skrill.
Serrated teeth,
jaw strength 17.
SNOTLOUT: I’ll avenge
your fallen limbs, big guy.
I’ll chop off
the hands and feet
- of every dragon that I see.
- GOBBER: Nah.
It’s the wings
and the tail you want.
If they can’t fly,
they can’t get away.
A downed dragon
is a dead dragon.
Anyone can get by
without the other bits.
SNOTLOUT:
I’m gonna lose all of my limbs.
I volunteer Ruffnut
to lose at least one limb.
Huh?
TUFFNUT:
What?
We’re twins.
Your pain is my pain.
GOBBER:
You’re twins?
Even our own mother
can’t tell us apart.
It’s uncanny.
There we go.
Astrid’s got the right idea.
Get your sleep while you can.
Soon, Stoick will be back.
And one of you will be chosen
to kill the dragon.
Question is: Who?
[grunts]
[air pumping]
♪ ♪
Toothless!
- [Toothless moans]
- [panting]
Brought breakfast.
[grunts, panting]
- Huh? What do you think, bud?
- [sniffing]
Okay.
We got some cod...
...some salmon
and a whole smoked eel.
- [distressed moaning]
- Whoa, uh, uh, uh...
No eel! Scratch the eel!
[panting]
Yeah, I, uh,
can’t say I love it, either.
[Toothless moaning gently]
That’s it.
Stick to the good stuff.
I’ll just be back here,
minding my own business.
Okay.
[grunting]
Okay. Okay.
[moaning]
Whew. Okay. Not bad.
It could work.
If it’s... Whoa! Okay!
Toothless, no! Oh, gods!
[Hiccup screaming]
Toothless!
Oh, gods!
[screaming]
[roars]
[frightened yelling, gasping]
[gasps] It’s working!
[laughing]:
Yeah! Whoo!
[yelps]
[squeals]
Yeah! Whoo!
GOBBER:
Today is all about teamwork.
If you work together,
you might just survive.
You see, a wet dragon head
cannot light its fire.
But a Hideous Zippleback
is extra tricky,
’cause one head breathes gas
and the other head lights it.
Your job is to know
which is which.
Good luck.
[dragon snarling quietly]
Razor-sharp fangs that inject
venom for predigestion.
- Prefers to keep its victims...
- Shh!
[whispers]:
...conscious.
You know, I’m kind of glad
we got partnered.
Us girls got to stick together.
- Until I have to take you out.
- Shush.
SNOTLOUT: I think I’ve
pretty much won Astrid over.
I mean, she can barely even
look at me.
[chuckles] You came
to the right man for advice.
- I didn’t ask...
- If there’s one thing
the Viking girl brain
can’t resist, it’s...
- [dragon chittering]
- SNOTLOUT: Look out!
[Tuffnut gasps]
- ASTRID: Hey!
- RUFFNUT: It’s us, geniuses.
TUFFNUT:
Lightning reflexes.
I see hideous heads, I strike.
- [grunts]
- Ow.
[chuckles] Whoa.
Uh, make that
one hideous head, Astrid.
[dragon growls]
[all grunting]
[Tuffnut panting rapidly]
TUFFNUT:
Save yourselves!
Also known
to toy with its victims,
dismembering them
limb from limb.
Will you please stop that?
Fishlegs!
FISHLEGS:
Wrong head.
[Fishlegs whimpers]
Get out of there, Hiccup!
[grunts]
Oh, come on. [grunting]
- [dragon hissing]
- [Hiccup gasping]
[sparks crackling]
[sniffs]
[moaning]
Yeah. Back!
[grunts]
Run... Hiccup.
HICCUP: Don’t make me
tell you again! Yeah.
Yeah, that’s right.
Back in your pen.
[snarling]
Now, think about
what you’ve done.
[hisses viciously]
[whimpers]
So, are we done today?
J-Just because I have
some things I need to, uh...
Yeah, I’m gonna... I’m gonna
see you guys tomorrow.
♪ ♪
[chuckles]
Huh?
[chittering]
Hey.
Oh, come on.
Just try it.
♪ ♪
Whoa!
Oh, I’m gonna die!
Whoa, whoa, no!
No, please!
Just kind of angle yourself.
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, no! [yells]
[screams]:
Oh, come on!
[grunts]
[panting]
[sneezing]
[continues sneezing]
- RUFFNUT: Out of my way.
- TUFFNUT: Move!
Move, move, move,
move, move, move!
ASTRID: Watch yourselves.
Get in its blind spot.
SNOTLOUT:
I got it! It’s mine!
ASTRID:
No, don’t bring it over here!
[Tuffnut whimpers, grunts]
[sneezing]
TUFFNUT: Uh, little guy.
What is his name again?
- RUFFNUT: I don’t remember.
- TUFFNUT: Hey. Slow down.
- Are you trying to show us up?
- N-No.
I’ve never seen someone
take down a Gronckle like that.
I mean, I do it all the time,
but how did you learn?
Learn what?
What exactly was that?
Okay, see,
I-I’d love to explain.
It’s just, I left my axe
back in-in the ring.
Who’s a good boy?
Whoa, okay. [laughs]
Yeah, yeah? You itchy?
Is that the spot?
[Toothless purring]
[moaning gently]
[grunts]
[shrieks]
[dragon grunting]
[yells]
[moaning softly]
Hiccup.
♪ ♪
SNOTLOUT:
Yo, there he is.
Hey, Hiccup. [grunts]
- Okay.
- Hiccup. W-W-Wait.
- I have a proper question.
- So I’m thinking that...
SNOTLOUT: All it needs to be
is you and me in the ring.
♪ ♪
A Terrible Terror! [grunts]
[chittering]
[chuckles]
It’s like the size of my...
[grunts]
[groans] Get it off!
Get it off! Get it off!
[snarling]
[lively chatter]
[grunting fiercely]
[grunts]
♪ ♪
[wind whistling]
[Toothless moans]
[moaning gently]
[squeals]
[Hiccup grunts]
[grunting]
[Toothless moans gently]
HICCUP:
Ow.
[birds screeching]
♪ ♪
[quiet chatter]
And the other ships?
[groaning]
Dad!
I got it.
[grunts]
I missed you.
In, like, a super manly way.
I got so much to tell you
about the Trial of Flame.
It’s basically between... Dad?
Dad?
Da...
Okay, I’ll see you at home.
GOBBER:
So, no nest, then?
Not even close.
I hope you had more success.
Well, if by success,
you mean your parenting
troubles are over,
then, uh, yeah.
[laughter]
Did you hear the news, Chief?
[laughs]
- Everyone is so relieved.
- Good riddance to old Hiccup.
SNORTI [chuckles]:
Aye.
No one will miss that nuisance.
Hiccup is...
gone?
Yeah.
Yeah, most afternoons,
but who can blame him?
The life of a celebrity
can be very rough.
He can barely walk
through the village
without being swarmed
by his army of new fans.
[Gobber chuckles]
Who would’ve thought
he has this...
way with the beasts?
♪ ♪
All right, bud.
We’re gonna take this
nice and slow.
Here we go.
Position three.
Uh, no, four.
[roars]
You ready?
[Toothless roars]
Come on. Come on.
[birds screeching]
[chuckles]
[moans softly]
Yeah, look at us!
[yelps] Whoa!
- My fault. My fault.
- [Toothless squeals]
Yeah, yeah, I’m on it.
Position five.
Come on, bud.
Yeah. Go, baby!
Oh, this is amazing!
The wind in my...
Cheat sheet! Stop!
[whimpering]
Oh, gods!
- [screaming]
- [Toothless roars]
♪ ♪
[whimpers, grunts]
[straining]
- [Toothless roaring]
- [Hiccup yelling]
[straining]
[roars]
[grunting, panting]
[grunts]
[Toothless roars]
♪ ♪
Yeah!
[snarls playfully]
STOICK:
Son!
Dad! Uh, you’re back.
Uh, uh, oh...
Okay, uh, Gobber’s not here,
- so, um...
- I know.
Came looking for you.
You-you-you did? Uh, wh-why?
You’ve been keeping secrets.
I have?
Just how long did you think
you could hide it from me?
I-I don’t even know
what you’re talking...
Nothing happens on this island
without me hearing about it.
So, let’s talk
about that dragon.
Oh, gods, Dad.
I’m-I’m-I’m so sorry.
I-I was gonna tell you sooner.
[stammering]:
I just didn’t know...
[Stoick laughing]
[chuckles]
[continues laughing]
[chuckles] You’re not upset?
What? What?
I was hoping for this.
- You were?
- [laughing]: Oh, yes.
And believe me,
it only gets better.
Just wait till you spill
a Nadder’s guts
for the first time.
Or-or mount your first
Gronckle head on a spear.
What a feeling.
You really had me
going there, son.
All those years
of the worst Viking
Berk has ever seen.
Odin, it was rough.
I almost gave up on you.
And all the while,
you were holding out on me.
- [groans softly]
- [Stoick laughs]
Thor almighty.
Who would have thought
that dragon training
would have been
your place to shine, huh?
Ah, you might even win
Top Slayer.
Just like your old man.
- Who knows? [chuckles]
- [Stoick laughing]
You know... [grunts]
with you doing so well
in the ring...
I’m gonna... I’m gonna...
- Sit.
- Okay.
We finally have something
to talk about.
[Stoick chuckles]
So, I...
[stammers]
[both chuckle awkwardly]
Oh! Oh, I, uh...
I brought you something...
[grunts]
to... to, uh...
keep you safe in the ring.
Your mother would have
wanted you to have it.
W-Wow. Uh, thanks.
It’s half of her breastplate.
[Stoick chuckles]
Matching set.
Keeps her...
It keeps her close, you know?
Wear it proudly, son.
You’ve held up
your end of the deal.
[yawns] Yeah.
- Yeah. Tired.
- Yeah, I’m gonna...
- I’m gonna get some s-sleep.
- Uh, good talk.
- Big day tomorrow.
- Yeah. [stammers]
The Trial of Flame,
and it takes a lot out of you.
Yeah, Trial of Flames--
Flame. [chuckles]
- Good luck with that.
- Yeah, thank you, thank you
- for the, uh... the breast hat.
- I hope you like the...
- Hat. Yeah.
- Yeah.
Okay, well...
[chuckles] good night.
- [clattering]
- [sighs]
[chittering]
No more of your tricks.
- I’m taking Top Slayer today.
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
It’s-it’s all yours.
Top-Top Slay away.
Sorry.
[Astrid scoffs]
♪ ♪
[dragon snarling]
Last chance. Make it count.
[dragon sniffing]
PHLEGMA:
Come on!
- Go on, Astrid! You got it!
- Come on, Hiccup!
- Go on!
- Come on!
- [yells]
- [dragon moaning gently]
No!
Son of a half-troll,
rat-eating...
Glad to see
she’s handling it gracefully.
You!
[clanking]
Uh, okay.
- Later.
- GOBBER: Hey, hey. Not so fast.
- STOICK: Quiet down.
- No, I can’t.
- I’m gonna be late for, uh...
- What?
Late for what, exactly?
- STOICK: Another year...
- [whispers]: Shut up.
STOICK:
...and another Trial of Flame
has come to an end.
Elder Gothi has made
her decision.
The new Top Slayer will be...
- [crowd gasping]
- [Astrid gasps softly]
[clanks]
[crowd murmuring]
[cheering and applause]
[chuckles]
You’ve done it, Hiccup.
You won the Trial of Flame.
You get to kill the dragon.
That’s my boy!
[takes deep breath]
Hiccup, you won!
- [Hiccup gasps, grunts]
- [Gobber laughing]
HICCUP:
Whoa! Yeah.
Hooray me.
I can’t wait to...
Beat it and never come back.
All right, bud. Time’s up.
- ASTRID: My thoughts exactly.
- [gasps]
Wh-What are you, uh...
What are you doing here?
- Looking for answers.
- Huh?
What are you doing here?
Who’s Bud? Your trainer?
Did he dress you up in this?
Uh, I-I know
this looks suspicious,
- but f-funnily enough, I, uh...
- [rustling]
Uh, you’re right!
You’re right. I, uh...
I’m through with the lies.
I’ve been making outfits,
so, um, you got me.
It’s time everybody knew.
Just take me back. [groans]
Ow!
Why would you do that?
That’s for the lies.
[Hiccup grunts]
And that’s for everything else.
- [Toothless growls softly]
- [gasps]
HICCUP:
Oh, no.
Run. Run!
- No! No.
- [Toothless roars]
- ASTRID: What...
- HICCUP: Toothless, no!
Stop. It’s okay.
She’s a friend. She’s a friend.
[growls]
Toothless, Astrid.
Astrid, Toothless.
The, uh... the Night Fury.
[snarls]
[growling]
I wouldn’t.
We’re dead.
Hey. Where do you think
you’re going?
[panting]
♪ ♪
[yelps]
[screaming]
♪ ♪
[grunting, panting]
[birds screeching]
[Toothless growls softly]
ASTRID:
Hiccup! Get me down from here!
HICCUP: You have to give me
a chance to explain.
I’m not listening to anything
you have to say.
Then I won’t speak.
Just let us show you.
Please, Astrid.
- [Toothless growling softly]
- [Astrid grunting]
[grunts]
What is this?
Uh, it’s my design.
Yeah.
Pretty much the cocaptain.
[Toothless groans]
Then let’s get this over with.
You got it.
Toothless, let’s take her down.
Gently.
Nothing to be afraid of.
[Astrid screaming]
♪ ♪
Oh, nice touch!
I thought you were
his cocaptain!
I am! It’s a temporary
dragon malfunction!
[Astrid screaming, gasping]
We worked out a whole system,
remember?
[Astrid screams]
ASTRID: If we survive,
I’m gonna kill you!
[muffled grunting]
- HICCUP: And now the spinning.
- [Astrid screams]
Thank you for nothing,
you useless reptile.
Please just make it stop.
[Astrid screams]
HICCUP: I’m clearly not
the one in control.
ASTRID:
Then I’m sorry!
Toothless, I’m sorry!
[wind whistling]
♪ ♪
[moaning gently]
Fine.
You made your point.
It doesn’t change the fact
you have to kill one tomorrow.
But if we can change
your mind...
What?
You gonna take everyone up
for a magical ride?
It won’t erase what they’ve
done to us, Hiccup.
They hunt us, steal our food.
And one of them took my mom.
But do we just keep
killing one another?
As opposed to...?
I-I don’t know.
But you botched
our escape plan, so I’m gonna need a minute.
Well, I might
not snitch on you.
And we might not
drop you in the sea.
[Toothless grunting]
HICCUP:
Bud? What’s up?
What is it?
- Hey. Hey.
- [Toothless roars]
Get down!
[dragons snarling]
Toothless, get us out of here.
[dragons shrieking, snarling]
It looks like they’re
hauling in their kill.
Then what does that make us?
[hissing, snarling]
♪ ♪
[dragons shrieking, chittering]
HICCUP:
The dragons’ nest.
Oh, what my dad wouldn’t give
to find this.
♪ ♪
[chittering]
[rumbling]
[roaring]
What is that?
[deep roaring]
All right, bud, time to go.
♪ ♪
[pained shrieking]
ASTRID: I can’t believe it took
this long to figure it out.
It all makes sense now.
It’s like a giant beehive.
They’re the workers,
and that’s their queen.
Their alpha.
It controls them.
We got to find your dad.
No, no, no, not yet.
They’ll...
they’ll kill Toothless.
Astrid, we have to think
this through carefully.
Hiccup, we just discovered
the dragons’ nest,
and you want
to keep it a secret?
To protect your pet dragon?
Are you serious?
Yes.
Okay.
Then... what do we do?
Just give me until tomorrow.
I’ll figure it out.
- [grunts]
- That’s for kidnapping me.
Hey, are you gonna...
And that’s for everything else.
[chuckles softly]
♪ ♪
- [moans softly, grunts]
- What?
[crowd cheering,
excited chatter]
Well, I can finally show
my face in public again.
[laughter]
All right.
If someone had told me
that in a few short weeks,
Hiccup would’ve gone
from being, well, Hiccup...
[laughter]
...to placing first
in the Trial of Flame,
I mean, I would’ve tied them
to a mast
and shipped them off
for fear they’d gone mad.
- [laughter]
- And you know it.
[Stoick laughing]
But here we are.
My son has won the title
of Top Slayer.
No one is more surprised...
...or more proud than I am.
Today, my boy
becomes a warrior.
Today, he becomes one of us!
- [cheering]
- Yeah!
Yeah!
CROWD [chanting]:
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
- Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
- [sighs]
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
Hiccup! Hiccup!
- Watch out for that dragon.
- [chanting continues]
It’s not the dragon
I’m worried about. [chuckles]
Look, I’m gonna try
to put an end to all this,
but if something goes wrong
in there, just...
don’t get involved.
My dad respects you too much.
[chanting continues faintly]
Yeah.
But...
you have something I don’t.
Something none of us have.
So... I’m going
to stand by you,
come what may.
Come what may.
It’s time, Hiccup.
Knock him dead, son.
[crowd cheering]
CROWD [chanting]:
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
Hiccup! Hiccup!
- Go, Hiccup!
- [chanting continues]
Show ’em everything
I taught you!
BOTH:
Should’ve been me.
[sighs]
Whew. All right?
Good crowd, isn’t it?
CROWD [chanting]:
Hiccup! Hiccup!
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
[chanting fades]
[exhales softly]
I would have gone
with the hammer.
Just-just give him a chance.
[takes deep breath]
I’m ready.
[gate rattling]
[clunking]
[breathing heavily]
- [whooshing]
- [crowd cheering]
♪ ♪
- [snarling]
- [indistinct shouting]
[growling softly]
What is he doing?
I’m not gonna hurt you.
[dragon hisses softly]
I’m not one of them.
[crowd gasping,
murmuring quietly]
- Stop the fight.
- HICCUP: No.
You all need to see this.
They’re not
what we think they are.
We don’t have to kill them.
- I said stop the fight!
- [loud clang]
[shrieking]
[grunts] Out of my way!
SNOTLOUT:
Get out of there, Hiccup!
[rattling]
Hiccup!
[crowd gasping, yelling]
[grunting]
[roars]
SNOTLOUT:
Quick, quick! Grab his hand!
- Climb up.
- Hiccup, grab my hand!
- SNOTLOUT: Get up here!
- RUFFNUT: Hurry up!
SNOTLOUT: Get over here, man!
Just grab his hand!
♪ ♪
Astrid, get back here!
That’s an order!
[grunts]
- [growls]
- [Hiccup gasps]
STOICK:
Run!
[straining]:
Come on.
[snarls]
STOICK:
Hiccup!
[yelps]
[gasping]
[groaning]
[Toothless squealing]
[Toothless pants, squeals]
- [crowd gasping]
- Night Fury.
- VIKING: Night Fury!
- VIKING 2: He’s real!
[shrieks]
[crowd clamoring]
[crowd exclaiming]
[roars]
[hissing]
[clamoring, cheering]
All right, bud. Go on. Go.
- [shrieks]
- [Hiccup gasping]
VIKING:
Go, go! Get to the side of him!
[clamoring]
Get out of the way, Hiccup!
[clamoring continues]
[screaming, grunting]
No, stop.
You’re only making it worse!
[gate rattling]
Astrid!
[Toothless roars]
[groaning]
I got it. Go!
Stoick, he won’t hurt you.
[Vikings shouting]
[yells, grunts]
[clamoring continues]
- [Stoick grunting]
- [Toothless snarls]
No!
- [Toothless roars, hisses]
- [Stoick straining]
HICCUP:
Toothless!
Don’t.
[moans softly]
[grunts]
- Take it down!
- [clamoring]
VIKING:
Grab its legs!
- Hold it down!
- HICCUP: No!
- No, don’t hurt him!
- Stay back!
[panting]
[moaning softly]
And you...
[scoffs]
Put it with the others.
[whimpering]
- STOICK: I should have known!
- Dad.
- I should have seen the signs.
- Dad!
We had a deal!
I-I know,
but that was before...
It’s all so messed up.
So everything in the ring,
what, a-a trick? A lie?
No, I-I should have told you
before now.
Take that out on me--
it’s my fault--
but please
don’t hurt Toothless.
The dragon?
That’s what you’re
worried about?
Not the people
you almost killed?
He’s not dangerous.
He-he was protecting me.
They took your mother,
for gods’ sake!
If she could see you now
standing there with them
when they’ve killed
hundreds of us.
And we’ve killed
thousands of them!
- [grunts in frustration]
- They defend themselves.
That’s all.
They raid us
because they have to.
If they don’t bring
enough food back,
they’ll be eaten themselves.
There’s something else
on their island.
A dragon like I’ve never seen.
Their island?
You’ve been to the nest.
Did I say nest?
How did you find it?
I didn’t. Toothless did.
Only a dragon
can find the island.
No. Dad, no.
You don’t know
what you’re up against.
This is nothing like
you’ve ever seen.
You can’t win this one.
For once in your life,
would you please
- just listen to me?
- [grunts aggressively]
[grunts]
You’ve thrown your lot
in with them.
You’re not one of us.
You’re not my son.
[door creaking shut]
STOICK:
Ready the ships!
We sail at dawn!
[breathing heavily]
[distressed groaning]
[busy chatter]
[groaning softly]
♪ ♪
[indistinct shouting]
[groaning]
VIKING:
Forward on the leading line!
Swing it out slightly.
Here she comes. Easy.
Careful with the head.
- [muffled growling]
- Oh, careful now.
PHLEGMA:
Weapons loaded!
SPITELOUT:
Spare rigging aboard?
- Aye.
- Hoist the sails!
Aye, Chief.
- Ready the oars.
- Aye, Stoick.
We set sail for Helheim’s Gate!
Lead us home, devil.
[Toothless growls softly]
♪ ♪
[moans softly]
[wind howling]
I tried to stop them.
I ended up giving them
exactly what they wanted.
I should’ve just...
I should’ve killed him when
I found him in those woods.
It would have been better
for everyone.
Yeah.
The rest of us
would have done it.
So, why didn’t you?
- Why didn’t you?
- I don’t know.
- I-I couldn’t.
- That’s not an answer.
Why is this so important to you
all of a sudden?
Because I want to remember
what you say right now.
For the love of...
Because I was weak.
Because I was a coward,
because I wouldn’t
- kill a dragon.
- You said "wouldn’t" that time.
Whatever! I wouldn’t!
I’m the first Viking
in who knows how long
who wouldn’t kill a dragon.
First to ride one, though.
So?
I wouldn’t kill him because...
...he looked
just as frightened as I was.
♪ ♪
When I looked at him...
I saw myself.
Bet he’s really frightened now.
What are you gonna do about it?
Eh.
Probably something stupid.
Hmm.
Well, you’ve already done that.
Then something crazy.
That’s more like it.
♪ ♪
Sound your positions.
Stay within earshot.
SNORTI:
One length to your stern.
LOOGI:
On your starboard flank.
FUNGI:
Why aren’t they attacking?
Maybe they know
something we don’t.
Are you just a glutton
for punishment or what?
We have a fighting chance
this time.
Thanks to Hiccup.
GOBBER: How long
do you think we’re gonna...
- STOICK: Shh.
- [Toothless purring softly]
Step aside, Drül.
♪ ♪
[continues purring softly]
[grunting]
- SPITELOUT: Ship the oars!
- STOICK: Oars in.
[continues purring softly]
SNOTLOUT:
Okay, wait.
You just disgraced yourself
in front of the whole village.
- Why would we listen to you?
- ’Cause I said so.
Exactly. Pay attention, gang.
Look, my dad means well,
but he’s stubborn.
And he’s about to be
way in over his head,
so it’s up to us.
Us?
I can’t pull this off
without you guys.
And you all have
something special to offer.
Say no more.
You were wise to seek
the world’s most deadly weapon.
It’s me.
You’ve got a wild side,
and I like it.
Astrid, you’re
our strongest fighter.
We need you to lead us.
Lead us where exactly?
They left
with every ship we have.
Stick with me.
GOBBER:
Oh.
That’s where that went.
Stay low. Be ready.
♪ ♪
[breathing heavily]
[moaning]
[grunts]
[breathing heavily]
[distant rustling]
We’re here.
[growls softly]
[sniffing]
[trembling breaths]
- No, uh-uh.
- [snarls]
Hiccup, I...
Relax.
It’s okay.
[moaning softly]
[growls]
Uh, where are you going?
HICCUP: You’re gonna need
something to help you hold on.
Get ready.
It’s gonna be a long night.
[grunts]
[dragons chittering]
VIKING:
Form a defensive line.
[grunting, busy chatter]
[tools clanking]
VIKING:
Sharpen those axes, lads!
♪ ♪
Chief.
Ready, Chief.
- Stand strong.
- Aye, Stoick.
- Make your people proud.
- We will, Stoick.
Today, we destroy
the reign of the dragon
once and for all.
However this ends,
it ends right here, right now!
[Vikings grunting rhythmically]
So let’s send these devils
back to hell!
[cheering]
♪ ♪
[Vikings shouting indistinctly]
[rumbling]
[breathing heavily]
[dragons chittering]
[yells]
- [Vikings yelling]
- [dragons shrieking]
[distressed moaning]
Is that it?
The nest is ours!
[Vikings cheering]
This isn’t over.
[rumbling]
[dragon growling]
Get clear!
Fall back!
GOBBER:
Fall back! Everyone, fall back!
♪ ♪
Retreat!
[frantic shouting, screaming]
Move!
[roaring]
[frantic shouting]
[growls]
[frantic shouting continues]
[screaming]
Get to the ships!
No!
[screaming]
[distressed moaning,
whimpering]
Get to the far side
of the island.
Aye, Chief. Let’s move!
This way! All of you!
- Get out of here, lads!
- Follow me!
Gobber, go with the others.
Why? Where are you going?
[grunting]
Actually,
I’m gonna stick around.
You’ve got that wild look
in your eye.
STOICK: I can buy them
some time if I give that thing
something to hunt.
And I can double that time.
[chuckles]
I know. I’m a big softy.
Softest part of you
is your teeth.
[growling]
[Stoick and Gobber
whooping and yelling]
[both gasp]
♪ ♪
[roaring]
[growling]
Remember,
that thing is their queen.
They’re inclined to do
whatever it says.
We’ve got to help them
fight back.
[gasps]
HICCUP:
Fishlegs, what do we got?
Ooh, uh, heavily armored
skull and tail,
perfect for bashing
and crushing.
Small eyes, large nostrils.
Relies on hearing and smell.
- Got it. Astrid.
- ASTRID: Okay.
Snotlout, Fishlegs,
hang in its blind spot.
Make some noise.
Keep it confused.
Ruff, Tuff,
figure out its shot limit.
Make it mad.
TUFFNUT:
That’s our specialty!
FISHLEGS:
Try not to get killed, guys!
- [flame whooshing]
- [screaming]
Uh, this thing doesn’t have
a blind spot.
There!
[grunts] Hey, bud.
[stammering]:
I’m good.
Be careful.
- [coughing]
- [Toothless moaning softly]
I know, I know,
but I’m, uh... I’m here now.
[Toothless moaning, whining]
- [snarling]
- [grunting]
[grunting]
SNOTLOUT:
Keep hammering!
But we’re confusing
our own dragons!
SNOTLOUT:
Oh, no!
[Snotlout screaming]
- [grunts, groans]
- SPITELOUT: This way!
This way! Come on! Come on!
VIKING: Guys, keep moving!
Keep moving! Come on!
PHLEGMA:
Go!
Is that my kid?
- FISHLEGS: Snotlout!
- Come on! Throw it!
[grunting]
Whoa, girl. [whimpers]
Going down.
[grunts]
I’m okay.
[groaning]:
Less okay.
[growling]
- [screams]
- I got you, Fishlegs.
[yells]
[roaring]
What’s wrong?
Got something in your eye?
Yeah! Now, that’s a Top Slayer.
[Snotlout yells]
[grunting]
[Toothless whining]
[straining]
[Hiccup grunts]
[Toothless sputtering]
[grunting]
[exclaims]
[coughing]
[breathing heavily]
[Hiccup coughing, panting]
[muffled splash]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
[roars softly]
You got it, bud.
Hiccup.
I was only trying
to protect you.
I know, Dad.
Let me return the favor.
Whatever happens up there,
I’m proud to call you my son.
And that’s all I need.
Let’s go.
[Toothless roaring]
He’s up!
You two, get Snotlout.
I’ll distract the queen.
[growling]
That’s right. Eyes on me.
RUFFNUT and TUFFNUT:
Snotlout!
- [trembling breaths]
- [dragon growling]
Now!
Oh, you have got
to be kidding me.
[yelling]
Whoa!
[heavy, gasping breaths]
I can’t believe that worked.
[chuckles] Yeah.
[dragon roaring]
- [chittering]
- ASTRID: No, no, no, girl.
Fight it! Don’t listen to her!
Shake it off!
[grunts]
[shrieking]
[yells, grunts]
[grunting]
[pained groaning]
[yelps]
[grunting]
[pained groaning]
Astrid.
[grunting]
[yells]
[whooshing]
Did you get her?
[grunts]
♪ ♪
Go.
That thing has wings.
Let’s see if it can use them.
- [whooshing]
- [roars]
You think that did it?
[roaring]
Yep.
[indistinct shouting]
[roaring]
All right, bud.
It’s time to disappear.
- Here it comes!
- [flame whooshing]
Quite the chief you have
in the making there.
Aye.
♪ ♪
[roaring]
- [whooshing]
- [roars]
- [Vikings gasping]
[pained roaring]
Watch out!
Okay, time’s up.
Let’s see if this works.
Is that all you’ve got?
[roars]
Stay with me, bud!
Just a little bit longer!
Hold, Toothless!
Now!
[yells]
[sputtering]
[sparks crackling]
- [Vikings gasping, screaming]
- [explosive whooshing]
[whimpering]
Yeah, bud, we... No!
[roaring]
STOICK [faintly]:
Hiccup!
Hiccup?
Son?
Hiccup!
[Toothless grunts softly]
Oh, son.
[Toothless groans weakly]
[sobs softly]
I’m so sorry.
[moans softly]
♪ ♪
[dragon grumbling]
[soft, trembling breaths]
[moans softly]
STOICK:
Hiccup.
[grunting]
He’s alive. He’s alive!
[Vikings cheering]
Yeah!
Yes!
[moans softly]
STOICK:
Thank you...
...for saving my son.
Well, you know...
[chuckles] most of him.
♪ ♪
[sighs]
Hey, Toothless.
[grunts]
Okay.
[panting]
I’m in my house.
You-You’re in my house.
D-Does my dad know you’re here?
Oh, come on.
[Toothless moans softly]
[sniffing]
[moans softly]
[sighs]
[takes deep breath]
[groans softly]
- [grunts]
- [Toothless moaning]
Thanks, bud.
♪ ♪
Okay, here we go.
[grunts]
[breathing heavily]
[Toothless moans gently]
[dragon shrieks]
[panting]
Toothless, stay.
[grunts]
Hey, hey, hey!
Shouldn’t you be in bed?
[Vikings chattering]
Okay. Hold on tight, guys.
Here we go.
Whoa, whoa!
[whooping, laughter,
indistinct chatter]
[indistinct busy chatter]
Hey! Hey!
- There you go!
- [chitters playfully]
[dragons chittering]
- There he is! Oh, oh.
- Oh! Okay.
STOICK:
So, what do you think?
A few changes
since you’ve been out.
Flying back here was, uh, quite
an experience, let me tell you.
Wait, wait, you...
you rode a dragon?
Well... well,
that monster burned
all of our ships,
so we didn’t really
- have much of a...
- ASTRID: Hiccup!
HICCUP:
Oh, no.
What’d I do this time?
Ow!
That’s for scaring me.
Okay, is it always gonna
be like this? ’Cause...
And that’s for everything else.
You know, ’cause... ’cause I...
I-I could get used to that.
STOICK:
Yep.
Turns out all we needed
was a little more of this.
You just gestured to all of me.
Well, you know, most of you.
New leg is my handiwork
with just a dash
of your kooky flair
thrown in for good measure.
Here we go.
[grunts] Welcome home.
- You rebuilt it?
- Yeah.
I found your designs.
Not too bad.
- [snarling playfully]
- Night Fury! [laughs]
- Here he is.
- HICCUP: What is it?
What is it, huh?
- Want to take it for a spin?
- [squeals excitedly]
♪ ♪
HICCUP:
This is Berk.
You’d have to be crazy
to move here.
Even crazier to stay.
It’s not for
the faint of heart.
Whoo! [laughs]
HICCUP:
Any food that grows here
is tough and tasteless.
Come on!
HICCUP:
The people that grow here...
- Whoa!
- ...are even more so.
[laughing]
The only upsides are the pets.
While other places may have
ponies or puppies...
- Come on, bud.
- ...we have...
[dragons roaring]
...dragons.
♪ ♪
["You Are My Homeward" playing,
rousing orchestral backing]
♪ Luck, how she favors me ♪
♪ Through cold
and stormy seas ♪
♪ To reach
such wond’rous sights ♪
♪ I travel always forward ♪
♪ Ho, where the dragons play ♪
♪ No harm shall come our way ♪
♪ We sail for another day ♪
♪ Fare thee well,
you are my homeward ♪
♪ Love, you shall always be ♪
♪ The loving arms for me ♪
♪ No treasure can compare ♪
♪ No hardships make me
falter yet ♪
♪ Do not shed a tear ♪
♪ Bid me farewell, my dear ♪
♪ Fear not
for my heart lies here ♪
♪ I return
for you are my homeward ♪
♪ You are bringing
me homeward ♪
♪ You are bringing me home. ♪
[song ends]
♪ ♪
[choir singing faintly under
dramatic orchestral score]
♪ ♪
[slow, somber version of
"You Are My Homeward" playing]
♪ Love ♪
♪ You shall always be ♪
♪ The loving arms for me ♪
♪ No treasure can compare ♪
♪ No hardships ♪
♪ Make me falter yet ♪
♪ Do not shed a tear ♪
♪ Bid me farewell, my dear ♪
♪ Fear not ♪
♪ For my heart lies here ♪
♪ I return ♪
♪ For you are my homeward ♪
♪ You are bringing me ♪
♪ Homeward. ♪
[song ends]